Guide to the Nationality Rooms Program Office Files, Second Deposit, 1927-2012 UA.40.01a
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Events, 1942-2012; III.
  - Anniversaries, 1966-2012; 3.
    This subseries documents anniversaries celebrated by the Nationality Rooms and Cathedral of Learning, primarily through correspondence, photographs, and event programs.
    - Cathedral of Learning Anniversary, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 260)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Historic Marker, 2004-2006 (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Thank You Comments and Photo CD, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 262)
    - Nationality Rooms Program 80th Anniversary Hillman Library Exhibit, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - Nationality Rooms and Intercultural Exchange Programs 80th Anniversary Celebration, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 266-267)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Invitation Design, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 268)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Invitation Recipients, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 269)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Labels, 2002-2006 (Box 7, Folder 270)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary Program, Proclamation and Dance Groups, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 271)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Planning Logistics, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 272)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Cookies, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 273)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Cookie Table, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 274)
    - Nationality Rooms 80th Anniversary, Post-Event Feedback, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 275)
    - Women's International Club 50th Anniversary, Winners Questionnaire, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 276)
    - Nationality Rooms 50th Anniversary, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 277)
    - Nationality Rooms 50th Anniversary, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 278)
    - Nationality Rooms 50th Anniversary, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 279)
    - Nationality Rooms 50th Anniversary Mailing Lists, 1971-1976 (Box 7, Folder 280)
    - Nationality Rooms 50th Anniversary, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 281)
    - Nationality Rooms 40th Anniversary, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 282)
    - Nationality Rooms 40th Anniversary Mailing Lists, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 283)
    - Nationality Rooms 40th Anniversary, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 284)
  - Holiday and Open House, 1942-2012; 4.
    This subseries is a collection of materials that relate to the Holiday and Open House Events that took place within the Cathedral of Learning and Nationality Rooms. Files include correspondence, promotional materials, publicity, photographs, requests for rooms, floor plans for the events, programs, event time slots, and committee lists.
    - Christmas Carols, Undated (Box 7, Folder 285)
    - Christmas Languages, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 286)
    - Christmas, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 287)
    - Christmas in Many Languages, "Merry Christmas", 1978-1993 (Box 7, Folder 288)
    - Open House, General, 1982-2012 (Box 7, Folder 289)
    - Holiday Rooms Write Ups, Undated (Box 7, Folder 290)
    - Christmas in Nationality Rooms Nations, Undated (Box 7, Folder 291)
    - Christmas Information, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 292)
    - Open House Publicity, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 293)
    - Christmas Information Publicity Packets, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 294)
    - News Releases: Yearly Christmas Open House, 1983-1996 (Box 7, Folder 295)
    - Christmas Publicity, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 296)
    - Open House Publicity, 1980-1995 (Box 7, Folder 297)
    - Christmas Publicity, 1972-1983 (Box 8, Folder 298)
    - Christmas Decorating, 1998-2008 (Box 8, Folder 299)
    - Holiday Open House, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 300)
    - Holiday Open House, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 301)
    - Decorating Day, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 302)
    - Holiday Open House, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 303)
    - Decorating Day, 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 304)
    - Undecorating Day, 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 305)
    - Holiday Open House, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 306)
    - Decorating Day, 1993-2004 (Box 8, Folder 307)
    - Open House, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 308-309)
    - Decorating Day, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 310)
    - Undecorating Day, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 311)
    - Open House, 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 312)
    - Decorating Day, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 313)
    - Undecorating Day, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 314)
    - Open House, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 315)
    - Decorating Day, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 316)
    - Holiday Open House, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 317)
    - Decorating Day, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 318)
    - Undecorating Day, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 319)
    - Open House, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 320)
    - Decorating Day, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 321)
    - Christmas Open House, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 322)
    - Undecorating Day, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 323)
    - Menu Cover for Open House, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 324)
    - Open House, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 325)
    - Open House, Decorating, and Undecorating Day, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 326)
    - Open House, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 327)
    - Holiday Decorating and Open House, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 328)
    - Open House and Decorating Day, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 329)
    - Christmas Open House, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 330)
    - Christmas, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 331)
    - Christmas Luncheon, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 332)
    - Christmas Open House, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 333)
    - Christmas, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 334)
    - Christmas, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 335)
    - Christmas, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 336)
    - Christmas, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 337)
    - Christmas, Greek Room, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 338)
    - Christmas, English Room, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 339)
    - Christmas, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 340)
    - Christmas, Finnish Room, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 341)
    - Christmas, German Room, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 342)
    - Christmas, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 343)
    - Christmas, Lithuanian Room, 1971-1980 (Box 9, Folder 344)
    - Christmas, Romanian Room, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 345)
    - Christmas, Greek Room, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 346)
    - Christmas, Yugoslavian Room, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 347)
    - Christmas, Hungarian Room, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 348)
    - Christmas, Scottish Room, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 349)
    - Christmas, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 350)
    - Christmas, English Room, 1972-1975 (Box 9, Folder 351)
    - Christmas, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 352)
    - Christmas, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 353)
    - Christmas, Polish Room, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 354)
    - Christmas, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 355)
    - Christmas, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 356)
    - Christmas, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 357)
    - Christmas, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 358)
    - Christmas, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 359)
    - Christmas, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 360)
    - Christmas, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 361)
    - Christmas, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 362)
    - Christmas, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 363)
    - Christmas, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 364)
    - Christmas, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 365)
    - Christmas, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 366)
    - Christmas, 1942-1957 (Box 9, Folder 367)
  - Event Committee Member Lists, 1976-2010; 2000-2010; 5.
    This subseries is comprised of committee member lists for each of the Nationality Rooms, which often include member names and contact information. There is also some correspondence regarding committee member changes.
    - Membership Lists, 2002-2010 (Box 9, Folder 368)
    - African Heritage Membership List, 1991-2007 (Box 9, Folder 369)
    - Armenian Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 370)
    - Austrian Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 371)
    - Chinese Committee, 1966-2004, c.2010; 1966-2004 (Box 9, Folder 372)
    - Czechoslovak Committee, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 373)
    - Danish Membership, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 374)
    - English Committee Membership, 1976-2010 (Box 9, Folder 375)
    - Finnish Committee Membership, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 376)
    - French Committee Membership, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 377)
    - German Committee Membership, 2000-2010 (Box 9, Folder 378)
    - Greek Committee Membership, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 379)
    - Hungarian Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 380)
    - Indian Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 381)
    - Irish Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 382)
    - Israeli Heritage Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 383)
    - Italian Committee Members, 1997-2010 (Box 9, Folder 384)
    - Latin American Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 385)
    - Lithuanian Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 386)
    - Norwegian Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 387)
    - Russian Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 388)
    - Swiss Membership List, 2010-2011 (Box 9, Folder 389)
    - Scandinavian Society in Western Pennsylvania Membership List, 2003-2010 (Box 9, Folder 390)
    - Turkish Membership List, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 391)
    - Turkish Alumnus, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 392)
    - Welsh Membership List, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 393)
    - Women's International Committee Membership List, 2000-2010 (Box 9, Folder 394)
    - Yugoslav Membership, c.2010 (Box 9, Folder 395)
  - Additional Events, 1960-2011; 6.
    This subseries contains correspondence, photographs, and publicity materials for a variety of one-time events that took place at the Cathedral of Learning, Nationality Rooms, or at institutions related in some fashion to the Nationality Rooms. Classroom dedications, classroom materials auction, presentation guides, exhibits, and other events are represented.
    - Special Events, 2010-2011 (Box 9, Folder 396)
    - Welsh Room Dedication, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 397)
    - Hillman Library Display Case, 1983-2007 (Box 9, Folder 398)
    - Auction, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 399)
    - Nationality Rooms Catalog, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 400)
    - Lace Day, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 401)
    - Frick Fine Arts Museum, 1984-1989 (Box 9, Folder 402)
    - David Lawrence Memorial Award Luncheon, 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 403)
    - Slide Presentation, 1970-1989 (Box 9, Folder 404)
    - Slide Presentation: Orders, 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 405)
    - Slide Presentation: Script, Care of, How to give, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 406)
    - Slide Presentations, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 407)
    - Ethnic Arts Project, Kent State University, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 408)
    - Ethnic Music Festival, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 409)
    - Visitor Center Display, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 410)
    - Hunt Botanical Exhibit, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 411)
    - Annual Giving Fund, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 412)
    - Urban 13, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 413)
    - Robert Morris College and International Newsletter, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 414)
    - Unitarian Church, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 415)
    - William Hung, Scroll Presentation, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 416)
    - David L. Lawrence Hall Floor Plan and Dedication, 1960-1971 (Box 9, Folder 417)
- Publicity, 1937-2011; IV.
  This series contains publicity materials regarding the Nationality Rooms, Cathedral of Learning, University of Pittsburgh, and City of Pittsburgh. Materials include local, national and international newspapers, newsletters, pamphlets, books, magazines, and correspondence.
  - Newsletters, 1959-2009; 1.
    This subseries is a collection of the newsletters published and distributed by the Nationality Rooms program. A Nationality Room was highlighted for each publication.
    - Newsletters, 1959-1975 (Box 10, Folder 418)
    - Newsletters, 1975-1984 (Box 10, Folder 419)
    - Newsletters, 1985-1995 (Box 10, Folder 420)
    - Newsletters, 1996-2003 (Box 10, Folder 421)
    - Newsletters, 2003-2009 (Box 10, Folder 422)
  - Cathedral of Learning Publicity, 1937-2011; 2.
    This subseries documents publicity regarding the Cathedral of Learning. Information concerning the building's funding, construction, completion, room dedications, ghost stories, and publications regarding the Cathedral of Learning and Nationality Rooms compose this subseries.
    - Nationality Rooms Book, Undated (Box 10, Folder 423)
    - Blue and Gold Building, Undated (Box 10, Folder 424)
    - Secrets of the Cathedral of Learning, 2009-2011 (Box 10, Folder 425)
    - Cathedral of Learning History, 1979-2010 (Box 10, Folder 426)
    - Cathedral of Learning Publicity, ca. 1937-2010 (Box 10, Folder 427)
    - Cathedral of Learning DVD, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 428)
    - Nationality Rooms History, 19938-2003 (Box 10, Folder 429)
    - History Channel, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 430)
    - Cathedral of Learning News Articles, 1970-1985 (Box 10, Folder 431)
    - Geise Proposal, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 432)
    - Presentation of the Scottish, German, Swedish, and Russian Rooms, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 433)
  - General Publicity, 1949-2009; 3.
    This subseries contains general publicity regarding the Nationality Rooms and the City of Pittsburgh. Correspondence for one-time events; news stories from local, national, and international sources; magazines; and room dedications are found within this subseries.
    - Newspapers, Language, Undated (Box 10, Folder 434)
    - Heinz Chapel, Undated (Box 10, Folder 435)
    - Publicity, December 2009 (Box 10, Folder 436)
    - Publicity, November 2009 (Box 10, Folder 437)
    - Publicity, October 2009 (Box 10, Folder 438)
    - Publicity, September 2009 (Box 10, Folder 439)
    - Publicity, August 2009 (Box 10, Folder 440)
    - Publicity, June 2009 (Box 10, Folder 441)
    - Publicity, May 2009 (Box 10, Folder 442)
    - Publicity, April 2009 (Box 10, Folder 443)
    - Publicity, March 2009 (Box 10, Folder 444)
    - Publicity, January 2009 (Box 10, Folder 445)
    - Publicity, December 2008 (Box 10, Folder 446)
    - Publicity, November 2008 (Box 10, Folder 447)
    - Publicity, October 2008 (Box 10, Folder 448)
    - Publicity, September 2008 (Box 10, Folder 449)
    - Publicity, August 2008 (Box 10, Folder 450)
    - Publicity, July 2008 (Box 10, Folder 451)
    - Publicity, June 2008 (Box 10, Folder 452)
    - Publicity, May 2008 (Box 10, Folder 453)
    - Publicity, April 2008 (Box 11, Folder 454)
    - Publicity, March 2008 (Box 11, Folder 455)
    - Publicity, February 2008 (Box 11, Folder 456)
    - Publicity, January 2008 (Box 11, Folder 457)
    - Moscow State University, 2003-2006 (Box 11, Folder 458)
    - Publicity Magazines, 1998-2004 (Box 11, Folder 459)
    - Carnegie Magazine, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 460)
    - Pittsburgh Publicity, 1949-1969 (Box 11, Folder 461)